So far, you've used fast
rules-based evaluations that
are suitable for running
frequently on every commit.
For stages of development
leading up to deployment,
more robust and comprehensive
evaluation methods can help you better
ensure overall quality before
you deploy the app to users.
One such method is
model-graded evaluation,
where you'll use an LLM
to evaluate the LLM app.
Let's take a look at this
kind of eval and how to
automate this as part of
your testing pipeline.
OK, until now, we've been
using rules-based evals
to make sure our models
follow the guidelines
we set up in our prompt and stick to
the facts we provided in our data set.
But in order to have full
confidence in our application,
we also need to be sure our
model is generating high-quality,
contextually appropriate responses.
Evaluating LLM output
can be tricky because
a good response to a query is subjective.
We could try and write custom
rules like we did for our initial
evals to make sure that
expected data is in the output,
but this gets more and
more complicated and more
and more fragile as the application grows.
One approach to checking the output of
an LLM is to use another LLM as a grader.
This is referred to as
model graded evaluation.
We'll show a quick
example to make sure our model
is actually producing output as a quiz.
We aren't concerned
with the content just yet,
only that the LLM is giving back
responses that look like a set of quiz questions.
We'll look more closely at the
quality of output in our next lesson.
So, in this lesson, we're
going to focus on judging
whether the response is
in the desired format.
And then, in our next lesson,
we'll look at things like
hallucination and adherence.
So, let's jump right in,
and write a passing and
a failing test case to see how this works.
First off we need to
establish our keys again as we
did in the previous
lesson so we'll do that now.
For the purposes of
adding model graded evals,
we're going to continue to use the
application that we generated in the last lesson.
So, let's take another look at that
just to remember what we're working on.
Again, you can use the cat
command if you want to see the
contents of one of these
files on your local file system.
They're all included with
the lab that you have. Now,
let's look at what it looks
like to build a model graded eval.
This is going to look similar to the work
that we did to build the quiz assistant,
except in this case, we are
building a prompt that tells
the LLM to evaluate the
output of the quiz assistant.
So, you can see here that we're giving
specific instructions to the LLM to tell
it the role that it plays in
evaluating the work of the quiz assistant.
Before evaluating an
actual quiz assistant,
we are going to simulate
this by writing an LLM response
as if it came from the quiz assistant and
using our eval to
determine if that response would
pass the test that we're looking to make.
As you can see here, the
full message or prompt
for the eval is telling
the LLM to evaluate a
generated quiz based on
the context and determine
whether or not it
looks like a quiz or test.
It is not meant to evaluate
whether the information is correct.
Then, it is told specifically to
output a Y if the response is a quiz,
and N if the response
does not look like a quiz.
Now, we are going to use
langchain to build the familiar
chain that we saw in the previous lesson,
except this time we're building a
chain specifically to do the evaluation.
So first, we have our chat prompt
template as we built previously.
Next, we select our LLM, which
also we did in the previous lesson.
And again, we're using GPT 3.5 Turbo.
And finally, we select an output parser,
which again is the STR output
parser to take the response
from the LLM and generate a basic string.
We chain these together as we
did previously, but to recap,
we take the eval prompt,
we pipe it to the LLM,
we take that response
and pipe it to the output
parser to get the string
that we're looking for.
So now, we've built a basic eval
chain using a known good LLM response,
And as you can see in
this case, we get a Y,
which means the known good
response that we put in is believed
by the LLM to look like a quiz
in the format that's expected.
However, we also want to ensure that it
will fail if it doesn't look like a quiz.
In order to do that, we'll first
store all of the eval chain creation
code as a utility function
so we can use it repeatedly.
Next, we store a known bad result so
that we can pass it into a new eval chain.
And now, we invoke this new eval chain
and see that we get the correct response,
which is an N to indicate that the
text does not look like a quiz. Now,
we're gonna take our newly created model
graded eval capability and incorporate it
into the tests that we're running inside
of our continuous integration pipeline.
So, we have two files for testing
on the file system in the lab.
The first is
testassistant.py which you can see
here and is what we
were running previously.
The second is test-release-evals.py which
is a roll-up of all of the work we just
did to show how to create a
model-graded eval and execute it against OpenAI.
Okay, so now that we have the
release evals which are the model-graded
evals stored in the
test-release-evals.py file,
along with the previous files
we had, the test assistant,
and the app where we
stored our original code.
We're gonna push all of
that to GitHub. And then,
to CircleCI so that we can
evaluate our application
including the model-graded evals.
Now, in this particular case,
we are using the full
evaluation for the positive case,
but intentionally passing the known bad
result to the negative case to show what
it looks like when there's a failure
in the continuous integration pipeline.
We are also only going to trigger
the release evals job on CircleCI
so that we don't do as much
testing for this particular example.
We do this through this
function, triggerReleaseEvals,
which uses a parameter
passed to the workflow.
You can see here that the only job that
is running is the runPreReleaseEvals,
because that was the one we
specifically selected through that parameter.
So, as you can see, we ran the
model graded evals in this run,
and we did get a failure because we
intentionally passed the known bad content great so you can see that your pre-release
evals run when you merge
your application changes to
the main branch in a
real-world development scenario
this would happen after
you've made changes on your dev
branch and run your per
commit evals we're setting up a
system to progressively
increase our confidence in the
application as we get
closer to releasing it to users.
In our next lesson, we'll
look at ways that you can
make the pre-release
checks even more robust,
including running
evaluations on multiple data points,
writing evaluations to detect
hallucinations in your application,
and storing evaluation results
for human review in CircleCI.
I'll see you in the next lesson.